VALERIO MATTERA



Senior Front End Engineer

16 Woodlands Chase, Witchford, Ely CB6 2SB, UK • +44 7402 588815 • https://valeriomattera.com • info@valeriomattera.com • linkedin.com/in/valerio-mattera

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I thrive on challenges and find always joy in solving complex problems. With an inherent love for my job, I approach each task with enthusiasm and dedication. As a super-fast learner, I eagerly embrace new technologies, constantly expanding my expertise. My love for learning drives me to stay at the forefront of innovation in my field and continually expand my domain expertise.

EXPERIENCE

383 Project

Senior Front End Engineer

August 2022 - Current

- Played a pivotal role in the re-engineering of the React Native Worcester Bosch Professional App, introducing modern technologies and best practices. Achieved an 80% reduction in errors and a 50% increase in user satisfaction.
- Innovated and constructed bespoke Microsoft Teams and Slack applications for a globally renowned journal: engineered a robust Node.js API to deliver content to the Slack client, alongside a tailored React app for Teams integration.
- Successfully overhauled the legacy React codebase for Worcester Bosch FastTrack, resulting in a remarkable 98% increase in conversion rates, elevated completed orders, and a revenue boost of £600,000. Implemented new designs, addressed bugs, transitioned from class-based components to function components with hooks, introduced Storybook for isolated component development.
- Conceptualized and developed a cutting-edge full-stack prototype for an Al-driven tool, empowering the 383 product team in analyzing and generating reports derived from customer interviews, to reduce the time spent by the team by up to 75%.
- Engineered a robust code of conduct documentation platform utilizing the Astro framework to
 empower 383 Front-End Engineers. Defined comprehensive standard operating procedures and best
 practices, ensuring adherence to industry standards and enhancing team efficiency. Additionally,
 authored informative articles and guides elucidating optimal practices for setting up front end
 projects, providing in-depth insights into tool configurations including ESLint, Husky, Prettier, and
 Storybook, ending in a reduction of setup times by up to 80%.
- Took charge of defining and implementing the future front end tech stack for the company, with a focus on CMS solutions such as Builder.io, Sanity.io, and Contentful.

Front End Engineer January 2022 - July 2022

• Led the delivery of the first direct-to-consumer e-commerce platform for Glenmorangie, generating over 100k during the first three months, crafted using Shogun Frontend, Shopify and Next.JS.

- Introduced a series of enhancements and new features to the Canvas wesbite, developed with Next.js (Pages router) project, supported by a Laravel Nova backend.
- Collaborated closely with back-end developers and project management to efficiently identify and resolve coding issues stemming from SLA tickets, consistently meeting or exceeding resolution timelines.

Lightbox Digital

Web Developer

November 2021 - January 2022

- Headed the successful delivery of the WordPress whg Housing Association website, leading its
 development and launch, achieving completion in just two-thirds of the projected time.
- Supported the tech lead in training two junior team members, fostering their skill development and facilitating a seamless onboarding process, resulting in a smoother integration into the team.
- Collaborated with the sales team by providing assistance in the preparation of quotations and estimations, contributing to the overall sales process.

Lightbox Digital

Junior Web Developer

April 2021 - October 2021

- Successful delivered the Millennium Point conference and events venue website.
- Continuously maintained and implemented new features on existing websites, ensuring their functionality to evolving requirements.
- Debugged issues on existing websites, addressing and resolving technical challenges to maintain optimal performance and user experience.

SKILLS

Core Skills: TypeScript • JavaScript (ES6+) • HTML • CSS • PHP

Front End: React • Next.js • React Native • Tailwindcss • Redux • Redux Toolkit • RTK Query •

Remix • React Query • Chakra UI • Styled components • Emotion • Framer motion • Gatsby • Astro

Back End: Node.js • Express.js • tRPC • Prisma • MySQL • MongoDB • REST API • WordPress **Miscellaneous:** Source control (Git) • Jest • ESLint • Husky • OpenAI • React Testing Library •

Figma • Mixpanel • Docker • Cypress

EDUCATION

Mechanical Engineering

University of Naples Federico II, Naples